Malesela Tlou Setwaba

081 866 7435 · setwabat3@gmail.com - www.marleyandme.vercel.app 44 Panorama Avenue, Kempton Park, Gauteng, South Africa

BUSINESS ANALYST & SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

IIBA-ECBA certified business analyst and full stack dev enthusiast with a strong track record of delivering value. I offer proven experience and knowledge in defining requirements and solutions, and communicating with stakeholders. Furthermore, I offer proven experience and knowledge in software development, specializing in web development and working as a liaison among clients and developers.

KEY COMPETENCIES

Process improvement

Data-driven strategic planning

Cost-benefit analysis

Report writing and presenting Critical thinking skills Excellent communication skills Strong interpersonal skills Proactive and self-motivated Exceptional organisational skills

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Department of Home Affairs - Digitization Project Technical Support

Jan 2024 - Present

Facilitated the roll-out of IT infrastructure by installing and configuring hardware and software. Troubleshooting and diagnosing multiple technical issues using root-cause analysis and providing accurate timely feedback. Defined and recommended time and cost-effective solutions to management with most solutions gaining approval. Provided easy-to-understand procedural documentation for system users.

Nelotec Pty Ltd.

July 2023 - Dec 2023

Software Developer - Remote

Developed quality software solutions adhering to functional and non-functional business requirements. Maintained collaborative relationships with internal and external stakeholders using regular and effective communication. Provided easy-to-read documentation and mentored junior team members. Participated in client and team meetings and recommended solutions to address issues.

TNG Solutions Jan 2022 - Dec 2022

Volunteer Business Analyst and Software Developer

Volunteered as an student/intern business analyst and software developer learning the foundations of working as a team and effective client relations.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Computer and Information Science

Majors: Business Analysis IIE MSA - NQF Level 7 - 2023

Entry Certificate in Business Analysis (ECBA) IIBA -2023

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Member and Volunteer

IIBA South Africa

Business Development Officer

Mototrace - Family Business